# Derek Moon

# Web Developer

Seattle, Washington p. (971) 319-2812 e. info@dmoon.co

w. dmoon.co

Front-End developer with over 7 years of web development experience within a variety of domains.

- Digital agency experience
- International live & work experience
- Higher education experience
- Project management
- Independent consulting

My most recent work has been on the agency side of web development, where most of my time is spent building stylish, functional UI experiences for our clients, which include some of nation's most recognizable non-profit and cause-driven organizations.

I contribute heavily to the development of our company's open source starter themes for the Wordpress and Drupal communities. My personal projects include a music suggestion engine and blog, a platform agnostic UI component library, a Wordpress plugin updater that encapsulates each update in its own Git commit, and a open-source Wordpress starter theme that adheres to BEM and SMACSS best practices and provides a bevy of Grunt-based task automation.

## **Skills Summary**

**Highly Proficient** > HTML5, CSS, SCSS/Sass, JQuery, Git, Grunt, Component-based UI Design & Development, Patternlab, static site builders, Wordpress, Twig/Nunjucks/Jade templating.

**Proficient** > OO programming using Javascript and Python, PHP, Drupal 6 - 8, APIs, web scraping, web analytics.

**Knowledgeable of >** Data Science methodologies, React, Angular JS,

Complete skills listing available upon request, or by visiting dmoon.co/resume

### **Experience**

#### Lead Developer & Founder / The Ardor Brio Company

JUNE 2013 - Present, Seattle, Washington

Proprietor and lead developer for the Ardor Brio Company, a digital agency specializing in custom content management system solutions, web application development, eCommerce solutions, and ongoing website maintenance and support.

Partnered with the Taylor Wilks Group to develop an internal assessment database for Women Accepting Responsibility, a Baltimore based non-profit org that provides emergency shelter and transitional housing for women, intake assessment referral, and HIV/AIDS counseling.

#### Front-End Developer / Forum One

JUNE 2015 - JULY 2017, Seattle, Washington

As a Front-End Developer at Forum One, I work with our project teams to build interactive, responsive websites and implement the award-winning designs produced by our creative team.

Develop custom themes, UI functionality and interactions for our portfolio of clients. Primarily using, but not limited to, various open-source content management systems, and some frameworks.

- Lead developer for WordPress projects. Refine our client's technical requirements & goals into a formal project plan. Coordinate additional technical team members for the duration of the project while actively completing development tasks.
- Deeply committed to the creation of front-end dev ops tools, to maximize the efficacy of our team to handle the amount of work that can accumulate.
- Contribute to the development of our organization's open source starter themes for Wordpress, Drupal, and Jekyll.
- Ensure section 508 accessibility compliance for federal clients.
- Work closely with our award-winning design team to transfer their designs into responsive code and templates for Wordpress, Drupal, and other CMS platforms.
- Work in both agile and waterfall settings. Participate in all stages of the product life cycle.
- Provide post-build technical support for our clients.
- Test front-end code in multiple browsers to ensure cross-browser compatibility, using industry standard unit, acceptance, and visual regression testing methodologies.
- Create HTML email templates and newsletters for email marketing campaigns.

#### Technical Project Manager / Forum One

AUGUST 2013 - JUNE 2015, Atlanta, Georgia

The Technical Project Manager (TPM) was the first of its kind position at Forum One, created specifically to satisfy the need for a client-facing, project-managing, web developer. As TPM I actively managed all aspects of the ongoing engagement with our portfolio of support clients. My typical day was spent working directly with our stakeholders to ensure a high level of responsiveness, and timely resolution of any technical needs.

- Introduced technical processes that resulted in a profitability level of nearly 30% for Forum One's support services, as well as the acquisition of two of the largest post-build support clients ever acquired by our organization. During my first 2 years on the job, our 3-person team generated over 13% of the total revenue for the entire company.
- Provided strategic advising and recommendations to our clients to help them realize their goals and maximize their impact.
- Performed development tasks, and provided technical support for client inquiries.
- Coordinated and resourced our support team members and contract staff to client projects.
- Facilitated client meetings, training, created reports & technical documentation.
- Established ongoing project plans with our clients, creating accurate estimates, and acceptance criteria.
- Coordinated a remote team of contractor developers.
- Administered the Forum One support Help Desk.

#### Web Developer / **Georgia Institute of Technology**

MAY 2012 - AUGUST 2013, Atlanta, Georgia

As the primary web developer for the College of Computing's Office of Communication, I worked very closely with a small, dynamic team of marketers and graphic designers to develop websites that fulfill the strategic communication and marketing goals of the College, its schools and research centers.

Developed and implemented brand refresh of the Georgia Tech College of Computing website in conjunction with the college's communication staff.

- Served as project manager for the upgrade of the college's Drupal 6 multisite which entailed a major content audit, and several functionality enhancements.
- Planned and implemented a standard operating procedure for developing new project and maintaining existing websites.
- Worked closely with the college's Technology Services Organization to implement a permanent web development infrastructure for testing and staging web projects.
- Introduced a content workflow to allow department's editors to control the flow of content to the website.

Additional details available upon request, or by visiting dmoon.co/resume.

#### Director of Online Programs / Language Link CV

JULY 2010 - MAY 2012. Praia, Cape Verde

In 2010, I relocated to Cape Verde in West Africa to help a small team of educators conceptualize and implement technical solutions to transform their business and classroom operations. This transformation that led to the creation of the country of Cape Verde's first blended learning program, and the creation of an online portal to facilitate their burgeoning translation business.

Additional details available upon request, or by visiting dmoon.co/resume.

#### Technology Buyer + Web Developer / **DePaul University**

AUGUST 2007 - JUNE 2010. Chicago, Illinois

Acted as primary purchasing manager for DePaul University's information technology equipment and software, a \$25-30 million annual budget. I also built and maintained the first iteration of the DePaul University salvage store website.

Additional details available upon request, or by visiting dmoon.co/resume.

#### Deployment Team Leader / Kraft Foods

MAY 2002 - MARCH 2007. Northfield, Illinois

Team leader for group responsible for the recoup/refresh/replacement of thousands of leased technology assets at Kraft Foods North American headquarters, and U.S. plant facilities.

Additional details available upon request, or by visiting dmoon.co/resume.

#### Education

**DePaul University / MSc.** Business Information Technology 2009. Chicago, Illinois

**University of Maryland** / B.A. Economics

2001. College Park, Maryland.

#### Volunteer

HERE Seattle / 2014-Present. Seattle, Washington